<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Jason Lollback</title><link>http://jasonlollback.com/</link><description>Jason Lollback's technology writings</description><atom:link href="http://jasonlollback.com/rss.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 15:13:03 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>nikola</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>My Custom Lockscreen</title><link>http://jasonlollback.com//posts/my-custom-lockscreen/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;My daughter found an iPhone 5, sitting abandoned on a park bench while we were out for a walk one evening. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the phone I was pleased to see that the owner had been security minded and had setup a 4 digit passcode, preventing any evil wrongdoing by anyone who happened to find their lost phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that having a passcode is less common than I thought, during the iPhone 5S launch while demonstrating the new fingerprint sensor Phil Schiller stated:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"In our research about half of all smartphone customers do not setup a passcode on their device and they really, really should."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is good advice, but the problem I encountered was that having a passcode meant that there was nothing I could do to identify the phone's owner, all that could be done was to report to the carrier that I'd found a phone belonging to one of their customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, once the owner realised that he'd lost his phone, he called his own number and we arranged to meet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to avoid this problem is to have your contact/emergency details on your iPhone's lock screen.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do this I use &lt;a href="https://itunes.apple.com/au/app/contact-lockscreen-info/id515658712?mt=8&amp;amp;at=11laQs&amp;amp;ct=blog"&gt;Contact Lockscreen Info&lt;/a&gt;, which I've used to create an image for my lockscreen that includes my wife's mobile number and my email address. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://jasonlollback.com/posts/images/my-custom-lockscreen.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has me covered for both an emergency contact or if I've lost my phone and it's found by someone inclined to do the right thing and return it to me. I also have my iPhone and iPad set to use the &lt;a href="http://support.apple.com/kb/PH2697?viewlocale=en_US&amp;amp;locale=en_US" title="Set up Find My iPhone"&gt;Find My Phone&lt;/a&gt; service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having your contact/emergency details on your phone will make it easier for somebody trying to help reunite you with a lost phone, having a passcode enabled on iPhones and iPads is essential, at least until we're all using devices with fingerprint sensors.  &lt;/p&gt;</description><category>ios</category><guid>http://jasonlollback.com//posts/my-custom-lockscreen/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 12:15:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Pilot</title><link>http://jasonlollback.com//posts/pilot/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Choosing a publishing platform for a personal website hasn't been a trivial process. I've had to work though identifying systems that would meet some basic criteria that are important to me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Low administration: Time should be spent on content and readability, not on infrastructure and databases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for a responsive design. Mobile and tablet devices have quickly become the primary way that digital content is consumed and separate mobile sites aren't a good experience for the reader.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speed:  Poor hosting, slow networks or underpowered infrastructure can all make for a slow website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Openness:  I want to have control of the data and the technical platform.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've found that the best fit for these requirements is a workflow based on a static site generator, which is a relatively minor evolution of how simple web publishing began.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Static Website Generator Workflow&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Write content in plain text files using Markdown formatting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The static generator converts Markdown to HTML.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upload HTML files to a hosting site, which could be a hosting service, GitHub or Amazon S3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;The static site generator takes my markdown formatted text files and converts them to HTML.  Index and archive pages are automatically created and final HTML files are then uploaded to a webserver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many implementations of static site generators which means that if in the future I want to switch to a different engine I'm not locked in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing is an essential skill for any technology worker.  Being able to manage a content publishing system complete with database infrastructure shouldn't be, which is why a static site generator is ideal for my needs.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>nikola</category><guid>http://jasonlollback.com//posts/pilot/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2013 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>